Komlan ZANKPE

Senior DevOps Engineer

DevOps Engineer with over **8 years** of experience in designing, implementing infrastructure, CI/CD and automation. At MEGA, I have defined the **DevOps strategy** to drive innovation and accelerate delivery. Laid the foundation to develop and deploy multi-tenant SaaS application. Beyond my technical expertise, I was the **primary advocate** for DevOps principles at the R&D leadership level.

Work History

2022-07 -Current

Lead DevOps

Mega International, Paris

Software company with solutions for Enterprise Architecture, Governance, Business Process Analysis

- Directed the cultural change by defining the DevOps strategy for the R&D
- Mentored a team of three engineers and improved team productivity
- Designed Azure landing zone for applications deployed to IaaS/PaaS
- Introduced more automation, tools and processes to ease products lifecycle and accelerate delivery: CI/CD with Azure DevOps, Pull Requests, Infra as Code with Terraform.
- Enforced best practices to ensure consistency and compliance

2021-06 -2022-06

DevOps Engineer

Thales Services Numeriques, Velizy

Company specialized in the design, development and maintenance of secure Information Systems:

- Contributed to the design and implementation of the Landing Zone with Terraform
- Implemented hybrid cloud architecture with Azure Arc
- Migrated workload to cloud using Azure Services Recovery
- On premises infrastructure assessment with Azure Migrate

2018-11 -2021-07

Cloud DevOps Engineer

Neocase Software, La Garenne Colombes

A leading provider of integrated HR and Finance service delivery solutions

- Migrated applications to Azure (Lift and Shift)
- Automated deployment with PowerShell scripts
- ARM templates and DSC used to build Infrastructure as Code
- Monitored client's application with ELK stack
- Developed custom PowerShell module for application administration

Personal Info

Address

66 rue d'Estienne d'Orves 93110, Rosny sous bois FRANCE

Phone

+33(0)695294930

E-mail

kzankpe@gmail.com

GitHub

github.com/kzankpe

Portofolio

me.kzankpe.com

Soft Skills

Agile Methodology

Critical Thinking

Teamwork

Continuous Improvement

Positive Attitude

Technical Skills

Cloud Management (Azure)

Configuration Management

CI/CD (Azure DevOps)

Version Control Software (Git)

ARM Template/Bicep

Terraform

PowerShell

Python/Golang

Windows server/IIS

MS SQL Server

Docker/Kubernetes

Unix/Linux

Prometheus/Grafana

API/Postman

2016-06 - Technical Implementation Manager

Ariane Systems, Pantin

A company providing online check-in/out technologies to the hotel industry.

Within the project team and collaborating with the development team:

- PaaS management: deployment and management of azure resources
- Deploy client environments using webservices
- Advanced technical support on the applications
- Wrote training documentation and guidelines

2014-02 - Field Service Engineer

Arelis Group, Colombes

Specialized in design and integration of electronic solutions

Working with the 2nd Authority for Television and Radio (Jerusalem).

Broadcasting DVBT and DVBT2 signal in Israel:

- Installation and maintenance of RF transmitters
- Network monitoring
- Storage and resources management
- Ensure client's expectations were satisfied

Education

2018-10

2016-03

2009-09 - Telecommunication Engineering, Master's Degree

2012-09 Institut Supérieur D'Electronique De Paris - Paris, FRANCE

Signal processing, Wireless networks, Electronics, Digital

communications, Web development ...

Certifications

2020-09 Az-104: Microsoft Azure Administrator

2021-02 Az-400: Designing and Implementing Microsoft DevOps

Solutions

2022-04 AZ-305: Designing Microsoft Azure Infrastructure Solutions

Projects

Platform Engineering

Create an Internal Developer Platform using the open-source tools available: Backstage, Azure DevOps/GitHub, Terraform etc...

Languages

French



English

